# **MRINMOY SONOWAL**

+447392712969; mrinmoy.mly.sonowal@gmail.com

ADDRESS: 44 Fairmont House, Needleman Street, London, United Kingdom

LINKED-IN: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrinmoys/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrinmoys/</a> GITHUB: <a href="https://github.com/mrinmoysonowal">https://github.com/mrinmoysonowal</a>

PERSONAL PORTFOLIO PAGE: https://mrinmoysonowal.github.io/

LANGUAGES: PROFICIENT: Python, Java, C/C++ | INTERMEDIATE: SQL, Swift, Dart/Flutter | Beginner: Objective-C, Haskell, JavaScript, React

### **EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS**

### UNIVERSITY OF EDINBURGH, BSc (HONS.) ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE AND COMPUTER SCIENCE

09/2019-05/2023

- Relevant courses: Algorithms and data structures, machine learning & deep learning, data science, software engineering, natural language processing, system design project, text technologies (information retrieval & text analysis), computer communication and operating systems.
- 2019-2020: Edinburgh Award (Work Experience) for creating a mobile app to connect university students during the pandemic.
- 2020-2021: Won the Institute of Physics award to promote diversity and inclusion. I mentored a group at Hello World Hackathon to build a website (using **HTML**, **CSS**, and **Firebase**) to promote tutoring.
- Final grade pending due to marker strikes on track for a 1<sup>st</sup> class.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# **DEMONSTRATOR - UNIVERSITY OF EDINBURGH**

09/2021-05/2023

- Run university classes to teach algorithms and data structures, functional programming, introduction to computation, software engineering, nlp and computer systems.
- Achieved highest levels of attendance by delivering innovative lessons to teach these concepts.
- Skills: Teamwork, communication, problem-solving and leadership, programming in Python, Java, Haskell, nltk and logic.

### SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN - AMAZON, PRIME VIDEO, IOS

06/2022-09/2022

- Worked on the client facing macOS app with a scrum team delivered project updates and daily stand ups.
- Demonstrated **strong ownership** of the project including *going the extra mile* to ask sister teams about similar projects.
- Used internal CI/CD pipelines to build, test and deploy code on internal repositories.
- Used Git to maintain workflow, open code reviews, merge, and squash commits.
- Created and updated features by using **Swift** and **Objective-C** bridging classes, lifecycle methods and view controllers.
- Learned about operational tasks such as metrics collection and analysis, testing and bug fixing during a high paced live event (Thursday night football Prime).
- Skills: Teamwork, communication, project management, time bound delivery, Git, Xcode and iOS development.

# **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

### DISSERTATION - APPLICATION OF NETWORK SCIENCE IN HEALTHCARE

09/2022-04/2023

- Implemented stochastic block models (SBM) to create disease clusters each patient's diseases mapped to clusters. (Python)
- Clusters used as features to predict mortality among patients in pre-existing dataset.
- Cluster membership determined through set intersection of cluster diseases and patient diseases.
- Wrote maintainable code, gained research experience, handled sensitive data, and gained further ML experience.
- Achieved a 1<sup>st</sup> class result.

## **SEARCH ENGINE - STORYHUNTER**

09/2022-03/2023

- Developed a search engine using **information retrieval** concepts in a team of 6 with large scale data **(>100GB)** from the A03 website. **(Python)**
- Worked on retrieving data from SQL databases using coalescing and join queries to one data structure. (SQL)
- Implemented boolean, phrase and proximity search and built the ranked retrieval search using tfidf scores.
- Handled multi-client queries and server responses by developing application-level network using FAST-API.
- Reduced client server latency by 50% and enabled concurrency 1000+ search results under 1 second. (FAST-API)
- Wrote maintainable and neat code by structuring classes, commenting, *code quality* and coding conventions.

# **SHORTQ** (CO-FOUNDER)

06/2021-PRESENT

- Made an android app to handle patient queues during the pandemic. (Android Studio, Java, Firebase backend)
- Improved the payment system and thereby reduced user complaints by 25%.
- Reached **1000+ users** in the first deployment cycle, reducing crowding by 50%.
- Designed and implemented the profile class. (Android)
- Shifting to web-based app to improve user base, where I implemented the booking calendar. (React)
- Worked on analysis, design, implementation, maintainability, and code quality.

## **DRONE DELIVERY SYSTEM**

09/2021-12/2021

- Constructed an algorithm to efficiently deliver the orders to virtual *geojson* location objects avoiding no fly zones. (Java)
- Captured requirements by identifying key system states, stakeholders, use cases, and non-functional requirements.
- Developed the class, communication, and sequence diagrams for the system.
- Fetched JSON data from the Apache Derby server and interfaced it to the Java class using GSon.
- Implemented system level tests and unit tests for the respective use cases and overall system, using Junit5.

## **PROGRAMME REPRESENTATIVE – UOE SCHOOL OF INFORMATICS**

10/2022-06/2023

- Link between students and staff to improve the student university experience.
- Work along with the school representative and other reps to build solutions as a team.
- Handle student feedback and suggest solutions and ideas for the present and future.
- Skills: Communication, problem solving and leadership skills.

### **ANCHOR - SIAF EDINBURGH DUSSEHRA FESTIVAL**

10/2022

- Hosted in front of thousands along with members of the Scottish parliament and Edinburgh council.
- Presented performers and invited dignitaries on stage.
- Skills: Presentation, public speaking, creativity, teamwork, and event coordination.

### MENTOR/JUDGE - ADAHACK

10/2022

- Helped students with Hooper's data science challenge. (Python, data visualisation, machine learning)
- Judged projects from 30+ students.
- Provided meaningful feedback and assistance.
- Skills: Leadership, management, event coordination, and education.

### **INFPALS** LEADER

09/2020-05/2021

- Lead student sessions in an engaging activity filled way.
- Lead Git, Haskell and Leetcode sessions, interview preps and job hunt sessions.
- Received positive reviews from students and highest attendance out of all the peer groups.
- Skills: Teamwork, leadership, creativity, and communication skills.

### PROJECTS LEAD - EMBEDDED AND ROBOTICS SOCIETY

08/2021-03/2021

- Coordinated events online to direct students to use embedded systems.
- Used Python and Arduino (virtual environment) to simulate basic devices.
- Skills: Leadership, management, and event coordination.

### **SPRING INTERN**

08/2020-03/2021

- Attended weeklong events by JP Morgan, Citadel and Morgan Stanley.
- Learnt about technology in financial markets and various market products.

### **ABOUT ME**

I am a hardworking, customer driven and resolute learner, who delivers quality work items in a time bound manner. I love to work in a high impact team to make QoL and important product changes. I have also developed a deep interest in scalable systems as proven by my work in both Shortq and Storyhunter. I have 3 years of mobile experience and I enjoy working on mini projects and coding challenges. Above all, I would love to work in a team that solves problems and makes a positive impact around the world. My hobbies and interests include travelling, hiking, attending socials and following current affairs. I am energetic, enthusiastic, and love learning from diverse experiences from people.

References are available upon request.